<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>jpp.sn</title>
    <link>http://jpp.sn/</link>
    <description>Recent content on jpp.sn</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-au</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2018 09:48:26 +1100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://jpp.sn/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Where to Cut the Tape</title>
      <link>http://jpp.sn/2018/02/where-to-cut-the-tape/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2018 09:48:26 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jpp.sn/2018/02/where-to-cut-the-tape/</guid>
      <description>In the 1980s and 1990s, radio journalists would record interviews on reel to reel tape machines. Standard equipment on assignment was a &amp;ldquo;portable&amp;rdquo; reel to reel tape machine the size of a suitcase and carried over the shoulder, as well as a bakelite microphone in the shape of an ice cream scoop.  Back at the studio, the interview needed to be edited for broadcast. To edit the interview, you would cut the magnetic tape at the start and end of where you wanted the cut, and then use sticky tape to join the two ends of tape back together.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tupaia, Polynesian navigator and translator, biography by Joan Druett</title>
      <link>http://jpp.sn/2018/02/tupaia-polynesian-navigator-and-translator-biography-by-joan-druett/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2018 09:17:57 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jpp.sn/2018/02/tupaia-polynesian-navigator-and-translator-biography-by-joan-druett/</guid>
      <description>This post is about an excellent book that I read recently, Tupaia, by Joan Druett, that tells the story of the life of Tupaia, a Polynesian master navigator and priest who lived in the 1700s. Tupaia navigated by sail across the islands of the Pacific, finding the way over weeks of travel on the enormous blue ocean using patterns in the stars, clouds, ocean currents, the flight paths of birds, and all the traditional expertise of Polynesian voyagers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Logbooks of childcare</title>
      <link>http://jpp.sn/2018/01/logbooks-of-childcare/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2018 23:10:48 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jpp.sn/2018/01/logbooks-of-childcare/</guid>
      <description>My daughter will start school next month, and this week she went to her old child care for (almost) the last time. At the end of the day she brought home two large ring binder folders.
 They were logbooks of her time at childcare. Until they came home that day, I didn&amp;rsquo;t know they existed or that the childcare teachers were making them each day. The books are full of notes, photos, artwork in clear plastic pockets, stories and quotes from the children.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Herds Of Giant Wombats Grazing</title>
      <link>http://jpp.sn/2017/12/herds-of-giant-wombats-grazing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2017 21:41:29 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jpp.sn/2017/12/herds-of-giant-wombats-grazing/</guid>
      <description>When you walk through the doors of the museum here in Melbourne, there is a gigantic entrance hall which contains the entire skeleton of a blue whale. Walking throughout the Museum, there are dinosaurs and insects, there are gemstones of translucent purple, milky blue, and a thousand other colours. There is an entire native rainforest in a room, with actual plants and trees and a pond full of fish. There is an extraordinary kids play room, with rope ladders going up a series of tunnels to a succession of rooms which go over your head and then back down again to the ground.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Electricity demand response at the Supreme Court (Demand response part 2)</title>
      <link>http://jpp.sn/2017/11/electricity-demand-response-at-the-supreme-court-demand-response-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Nov 2017 20:40:44 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jpp.sn/2017/11/electricity-demand-response-at-the-supreme-court-demand-response-part-2/</guid>
      <description>In part 1 of this article, I wrote about the importance of demand response in the electricity industry &amp;ndash; i.e., why power companies might choose to pay customers to use less electricity at certain times. Here, I discuss what the right price for demand response would be, and a recent US Supreme Court case over the fundamental economic principles of that price &amp;ndash; including the question of whether reducing consumption was equivalent to generation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paying people to use less electricity (Demand response part 1)</title>
      <link>http://jpp.sn/2017/11/paying-people-to-use-less-electricity-demand-response-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Nov 2017 20:40:44 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jpp.sn/2017/11/paying-people-to-use-less-electricity-demand-response-part-1/</guid>
      <description>In the electricity industry, where I work, it is important to keep supply (the energy being provided by the generators) balanced with demand (the energy being used by customers) at all times. If this is not done, the entire system will quickly collapse to and fail to what is called &amp;ldquo;system black&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;blackout&amp;rdquo;. This is different to the market for almost every other product or service. Consider, for example, what happens when Apple creates a new model of iPhone, but does not make enough so that everyone who wants to buy one on the day they are released is able to do so.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preparing For Monsters</title>
      <link>http://jpp.sn/2017/10/preparing-for-monsters/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2017 21:40:38 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jpp.sn/2017/10/preparing-for-monsters/</guid>
      <description>The other night I helped my daughter to make a cubby from the couch cushions to play in.
 Earlier in the night she had got in trouble for putting leaves from the garden into my bed, and then again for messing up my son&amp;rsquo;s train set. She wasn&amp;rsquo;t going to get any TV for the next few days, and was grumpy about it.
But later in the evening, things improved.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The best of the old and new swings</title>
      <link>http://jpp.sn/2017/10/the-best-of-the-old-and-new-swings/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2017 20:40:55 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jpp.sn/2017/10/the-best-of-the-old-and-new-swings/</guid>
      <description>At another park, upstream from our house, there are two excellent swings which the kids love to play on, one new and one very old.
 The old swing has a big diamond head, with the sculpted face of a friendly clown. The whole thing spins round and round, and the chairs swing out wider and wider the faster you go. These swings used to be quite common in Victoria when I was growing up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fast slides and good times</title>
      <link>http://jpp.sn/2017/10/fast-slides-and-good-times/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Oct 2017 21:39:59 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jpp.sn/2017/10/fast-slides-and-good-times/</guid>
      <description>Not far from where I live is a fantastic playground. There are swings, cubby houses, roundabouts, and in the center is an enormous tower with two slides down to the ground.
 The slides are made from metal, not plastic, so there are no static electic shocks and they are fast. The lower slide is ok for young children who can walk and climb, but it has a slight corner and they can come out sideways if they&amp;rsquo;re not careful.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Archive</title>
      <link>http://jpp.sn/archive/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Oct 2017 16:59:11 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jpp.sn/archive/</guid>
      <description>Here is the list of blog posts:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning By Heart</title>
      <link>http://jpp.sn/2017/10/learning-by-heart/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2017 07:47:19 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jpp.sn/2017/10/learning-by-heart/</guid>
      <description>When I was younger, I thought that learning things by heart was silly. Memorising facts, figures, names and dates, or a strict old authoritarian school teacher forcing kids to memorise the names of kings &amp;ndash; this seemed ridiculous to me. Better to understand the patterns of political history, or the underlying physics and equations of something. You will naturally remember the basic details of a topic as you study it, and that&amp;rsquo;s enough, any effort to specifically memorise facts is wasted.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ghost Bird</title>
      <link>http://jpp.sn/2017/08/ghost-bird/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2017 07:49:50 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jpp.sn/2017/08/ghost-bird/</guid>
      <description>Edit: a version of this post was published in the December 2017 issue of Australian Birdlife magazine.
A few years ago, in the middle of winter, my wife and I moved from our house in inner Melbourne to Cairns in Far North Queensland. Tropical Queensland looked instantly different to southern Australia. There was rainforest in the hills behind the town, and sugar cane growing along the highway. The sun in Cairns was strong and bright, and the landscape seemed to be an intense, rich green instead of the blueish-green, straw yellow and sandy brown colours of down south.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Help To Make The Thing</title>
      <link>http://jpp.sn/2017/07/help-to-make-the-thing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2017 09:49:09 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jpp.sn/2017/07/help-to-make-the-thing/</guid>
      <description>If you wanted to make a beautiful iron latticework clock for someone dear to you &amp;ndash; say for a 50th birthday gift &amp;ndash; or colourful glazed ceramics dish, or a wood dining table, it would not be easy to do if you had never done it before. It takes a huge amount of learning, trial and error, safety training, expensive equipment and so on, to make something like iron latticework or ceramics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What A Country</title>
      <link>http://jpp.sn/2017/07/what-a-country/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jul 2017 09:37:06 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jpp.sn/2017/07/what-a-country/</guid>
      <description>When our first child was born, a very nice nurse came to visit us every few weeks or so, from when we first got home to when our daughter was two months old. The nurse was friendly, helpful, did a health check, gave good advice, and was very much appreciated.
 After two months, the nurse stopped visiting us at home, but we visited her at her office every few months.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discovery Of Helium Under the Earth</title>
      <link>http://jpp.sn/2017/07/discovery-of-helium-under-the-earth/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2017 06:40:43 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jpp.sn/2017/07/discovery-of-helium-under-the-earth/</guid>
      <description>Another story from the discovery of helium is when it was discovered on Earth in large quantities. As I wrote in part 1, helium is so light that it will escape into space over time, and there is almost no helium in ordinary air less than (0.0006%). When helium was first discovered, it was trapped in tiny amounts in rock, where it had been created by nuclear reactions (for example, in uranium ore).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://jpp.sn/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2017 08:33:33 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jpp.sn/about/</guid>
      <description>My name is Matthew Jeppesen. I live in Melbourne, Australia. I am a co-founder of Proa Analytics and an honorary research fellow at Melbourne University. On twitter I am @matthewjeppesen.
This website is a personal blog, however, where I write about ideas and stories that interest me. The opinions and so on here are mine alone.
Back to the home page</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Helium was discovered on the Sun before the Earth</title>
      <link>http://jpp.sn/2017/07/helium-was-discovered-on-the-sun-before-the-earth/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2017 08:33:33 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jpp.sn/2017/07/helium-was-discovered-on-the-sun-before-the-earth/</guid>
      <description>As part of some barely work related research I have been doing, I read some new sources on the discovery of helium. I have always loved the fact that helium was discovered on the Sun before it was discovered on the Earth. It seems like an amazing thing &amp;ndash; an entirely new element was discovered in the Sun, which no one had ever knew of before, and then only 13 years later it was discovered on the Earth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Foot Surgery</title>
      <link>http://jpp.sn/2017/07/foot-surgery/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2017 13:34:36 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jpp.sn/2017/07/foot-surgery/</guid>
      <description>I have had foot surgery, and I&amp;rsquo;m lying in bed now, with my foot on a pillow, recovering.
 The surgery I delayed for a long time, over a year. Why delay then and why act now?
A year ago my left foot was been giving me problems. It would hurt for a few days, then get better. It could be after exercise, or for no obvious reason. I tried soft padded shoes and shoes with no padding.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>