<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on jpp.sn</title>
    <link>http://matthewjeppesen.com/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on jpp.sn</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-au</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2017 09:49:09 +1000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://matthewjeppesen.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Help To Make The Thing</title>
      <link>http://matthewjeppesen.com/post/help-to-make-the-thing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2017 09:49:09 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://matthewjeppesen.com/post/help-to-make-the-thing/</guid>
      <description>An idea for a creative online business.
If you wanted to make a beautiful iron latticework clock for someone dear to you &amp;ndash; say for a 50th birthday gift &amp;ndash; or colourful glazed ceramics dish, or a wood dining table, it would not be easy to do if you had never done it before. It takes a huge amount of learning, trial and error, safety training, expensive equipment and so on, to make something like iron latticework or ceramics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What A Country</title>
      <link>http://matthewjeppesen.com/post/what-a-country/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jul 2017 09:37:06 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://matthewjeppesen.com/post/what-a-country/</guid>
      <description>When our first child was born, a very nice nurse came to visit us every few weeks or so, from when we first got home to when our daughter was two months old. The nurse was friendly, helpful, did a health check, gave good advice, and was very much appreciated.
After two months, the nurse stopped visiting us at home, but we visited her at her office every few months. It was a great service, but we weren&amp;rsquo;t special &amp;ndash; every new baby in Australia gets this, as far as I know, tell, and it was absolutely free.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Helium was discovered on the Sun before the Earth</title>
      <link>http://matthewjeppesen.com/post/discovery-of-helium/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2017 08:33:33 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://matthewjeppesen.com/post/discovery-of-helium/</guid>
      <description>As part of some barely work related research I have been doing, I read some new sources on the discovery of helium. I have always loved the fact that helium was discovered on the Sun before it was discovered on the Earth. It seems like an amazing thing &amp;ndash; an entirely new element was discovered in the Sun, which no one had ever knew of before, and then only 13 years later it was discovered on the Earth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Foot Surgery</title>
      <link>http://matthewjeppesen.com/post/foot-surgery/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2017 13:34:36 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://matthewjeppesen.com/post/foot-surgery/</guid>
      <description>I have had foot surgery, and I&amp;rsquo;m lying in bed now, with my foot on a pillow, recovering.
 The surgery I delayed for a long time, over a year. Why delay then and why act now?
A year ago my left foot was been giving me problems. It would hurt for a few days, then get better. It could be after exercise, or for no obvious reason. I tried soft padded shoes and shoes with no padding.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>