<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>History on jpp.sn</title>
    <link>http://jpp.sn/tags/history/</link>
    <description>Recent content in History on jpp.sn</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-au</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2018 09:17:57 +1100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://jpp.sn/tags/history/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Tupaia, Polynesian navigator and translator, biography by Joan Druett</title>
      <link>http://jpp.sn/2018/02/tupaia-polynesian-navigator-and-translator-biography-by-joan-druett/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2018 09:17:57 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jpp.sn/2018/02/tupaia-polynesian-navigator-and-translator-biography-by-joan-druett/</guid>
      <description>This is about an excellent book that I read recently, Tupaia, by Joan Druett, that tells the story of the life of Tupaia, a Polynesian master navigator and priest who lived in the 1700s. Tupaia navigated by sail across the islands of the Pacific, finding the way over weeks of travel on the enormous blue ocean using patterns in the stars, clouds, ocean currents, the flight paths of birds, and all the traditional expertise of Polynesian voyagers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Herds Of Giant Wombats Grazing</title>
      <link>http://jpp.sn/2017/12/herds-of-giant-wombats-grazing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2017 21:41:29 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jpp.sn/2017/12/herds-of-giant-wombats-grazing/</guid>
      <description>When you walk through the doors of the museum here in Melbourne, there is a gigantic entrance hall which contains the entire skeleton of a blue whale. Walking throughout the Museum, there are dinosaurs and insects, there are gemstones of translucent purple, milky blue, and a thousand other colours. There is an entire native rainforest in a room, with actual plants and trees and a pond full of fish. There is an extraordinary kids play room, with rope ladders going up a series of tunnels to a succession of rooms which go over your head and then back down again to the ground.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discovery Of Helium Under the Earth</title>
      <link>http://jpp.sn/2017/07/discovery-of-helium-under-the-earth/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2017 06:40:43 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jpp.sn/2017/07/discovery-of-helium-under-the-earth/</guid>
      <description>Another story from the discovery of helium is when it was discovered on Earth in large quantities. As I wrote in part 1, helium is so light that it will escape into space over time, and there is almost no helium in ordinary air less than (0.0006%). When helium was first discovered, it was trapped in tiny amounts in rock, where it had been created by nuclear reactions (for example, in uranium ore).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Helium was discovered on the Sun before the Earth</title>
      <link>http://jpp.sn/2017/07/helium-was-discovered-on-the-sun-before-the-earth/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2017 08:33:33 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jpp.sn/2017/07/helium-was-discovered-on-the-sun-before-the-earth/</guid>
      <description>As part of some barely work related research I have been doing, I read some new sources on the discovery of helium. I have always loved the fact that helium was discovered on the Sun before it was discovered on the Earth. It seems like an amazing thing &amp;ndash; an entirely new element was discovered in the Sun, which no one had ever knew of before, and then only 13 years later it was discovered on the Earth.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>