<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Family on jpp.sn</title>
    <link>http://jpp.sn/tags/family/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Family on jpp.sn</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-au</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2018 09:48:26 +1100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://jpp.sn/tags/family/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Where to Cut the Tape</title>
      <link>http://jpp.sn/2018/02/where-to-cut-the-tape/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2018 09:48:26 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jpp.sn/2018/02/where-to-cut-the-tape/</guid>
      <description>In the 1980s and 1990s, radio journalists would record interviews on reel to reel tape machines. Standard equipment on assignment was a &amp;ldquo;portable&amp;rdquo; reel to reel tape machine the size of a suitcase and carried over the shoulder, as well as a bakelite microphone in the shape of an ice cream scoop.  Back at the studio, the interview needed to be edited for broadcast. To edit the interview, you would cut the magnetic tape at the start and end of where you wanted the cut, and then use sticky tape to join the two ends of tape back together.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Logbooks of childcare</title>
      <link>http://jpp.sn/2018/01/logbooks-of-childcare/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2018 23:10:48 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jpp.sn/2018/01/logbooks-of-childcare/</guid>
      <description>My daughter will start school next month, and this week she went to her old child care for (almost) the last time. At the end of the day she brought home two large ring binder folders.
 They were logbooks of her time at childcare. Until they came home that day, I didn&amp;rsquo;t know they existed or that the childcare teachers were making them each day. The books are full of notes, photos, artwork in clear plastic pockets, stories and quotes from the children.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preparing For Monsters</title>
      <link>http://jpp.sn/2017/10/preparing-for-monsters/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2017 21:40:38 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jpp.sn/2017/10/preparing-for-monsters/</guid>
      <description>The other night I helped my daughter to make a cubby from the couch cushions to play in.
 Earlier in the night she had got in trouble for putting leaves from the garden into my bed, and then again for messing up my son&amp;rsquo;s train set. She wasn&amp;rsquo;t going to get any TV for the next few days, and was grumpy about it.
But later in the evening, things improved.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The best of the old and new swings</title>
      <link>http://jpp.sn/2017/10/the-best-of-the-old-and-new-swings/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2017 20:40:55 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jpp.sn/2017/10/the-best-of-the-old-and-new-swings/</guid>
      <description>At another park, upstream from our house, there are two excellent swings which the kids love to play on, one new and one very old.
 The old swing has a big diamond head, with the sculpted face of a friendly clown. The whole thing spins round and round, and the chairs swing out wider and wider the faster you go. These swings used to be quite common in Victoria when I was growing up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fast slides and good times</title>
      <link>http://jpp.sn/2017/10/fast-slides-and-good-times/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Oct 2017 21:39:59 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jpp.sn/2017/10/fast-slides-and-good-times/</guid>
      <description>Not far from where I live is a fantastic playground. There are swings, cubby houses, roundabouts, and in the center is an enormous tower with two slides down to the ground.
 The slides are made from metal, not plastic, so there are no static electic shocks and they are fast. The lower slide is ok for young children who can walk and climb, but it has a slight corner and they can come out sideways if they&amp;rsquo;re not careful.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What A Country</title>
      <link>http://jpp.sn/2017/07/what-a-country/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jul 2017 09:37:06 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jpp.sn/2017/07/what-a-country/</guid>
      <description>When our first child was born, a very nice nurse came to visit us every few weeks or so, from when we first got home to when our daughter was two months old. The nurse was friendly, helpful, did a health check, gave good advice, and was very much appreciated.
 After two months, the nurse stopped visiting us at home, but we visited her at her office every few months.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>