<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Energy on jpp.sn</title>
    <link>https://jpp.sn/tags/energy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Energy on jpp.sn</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-au</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 17 Mar 2018 10:46:57 +1100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://jpp.sn/tags/energy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Solar power in space: Vanguard 1</title>
      <link>https://jpp.sn/2018/03/solar-power-in-space-vanguard-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Mar 2018 10:46:57 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jpp.sn/2018/03/solar-power-in-space-vanguard-1/</guid>
      <description>Today is an interesting anniversary: the sixtieth anniversary of solar power in space. On 17 March 1958, the American satellite Vanguard 1 entered orbit, becoming the fourth satellite ever to do so, and the first to use solar power. Vanguard 1 was small enough to be held by a person in one hand &amp;ndash; 1.5 kg (3 lbs) in mass and 16 cm (6&amp;rdquo;) in diameter, or 76 cm (30&amp;rdquo;) wide including the antenna aerials.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Electricity demand response at the Supreme Court (Demand response part 2)</title>
      <link>https://jpp.sn/2017/11/electricity-demand-response-at-the-supreme-court-demand-response-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Nov 2017 20:40:44 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jpp.sn/2017/11/electricity-demand-response-at-the-supreme-court-demand-response-part-2/</guid>
      <description>In part 1 of this article, I wrote about the importance of demand response in the electricity industry &amp;ndash; i.e., why power companies might choose to pay customers to use less electricity at certain times. Here, I discuss what the right price for demand response would be, and a recent US Supreme Court case over the fundamental economic principles of that price &amp;ndash; including the question of whether reducing consumption was equivalent to generation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paying people to use less electricity (Demand response part 1)</title>
      <link>https://jpp.sn/2017/11/paying-people-to-use-less-electricity-demand-response-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Nov 2017 20:40:44 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jpp.sn/2017/11/paying-people-to-use-less-electricity-demand-response-part-1/</guid>
      <description>In the electricity industry, where I work, it is important to keep supply (the energy being provided by the generators) balanced with demand (the energy being used by customers) at all times. If this is not done, the entire system will quickly collapse to and fail to what is called &amp;ldquo;system black&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;blackout&amp;rdquo;. This is different to the market for almost every other product or service. Consider, for example, what happens when Apple creates a new model of iPhone, but does not make enough so that everyone who wants to buy one on the day they are released is able to do so.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>